ASRAR AHMAD

Java Full Stack Developer

CONTACT DETAILS



+91 8149448939



asrar2602@outlook.com Mumbai, India

PROFILE

Full Stack Java/J2EE Developer with 2 years of experience developing robust code for high-volume businesses.

Spring MVC, Spring Boot and Spring Rest API Web Services 2 years of experience.

Received M.E degree in computer science & information technology from Amravati University, India in 2015.

Areas of interest are Data Mining, Machine Learning, NLP and Artificial Intelligence.

SKILLS



FRAMEWORKS

- Java Struts 2.0
- Spring Core
- Spring MVC
- Spring Boot
- Spring REST
- Hibernate

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant

Minsyst Consulting Pvt. Ltd

January 2019 - Present

Working with Java Struts 2.0 application ETIM (UPSRTC), designing, coding and writing web service API for android machines.

Developing ETIM Application & Web Service API for Android Machines.

Developing Business Intelligence Software & API for ETIM.

ETIM is a handheld Electronic Ticket Issuing Machine given to a bus conductor who issues tickets to passengers. This machine is loaded at depot level by web application written in Java Struts 2.0. Machine is connected via USB and then web application has to be started. In this we have to follow different phases starting from machine registration, route allocation, waybill allocation after waybill get allocated, machine get disconnected and given to conductor to start their duty. After completion of conductor duty he again submits the machine to depot then machine again connected to application for downloading the data from machine.

Working scope are Core Java, Web Services, Servlets, JSP and JavaScript.

Working with another application SLA (Service Level Agreement) written in Spring MVC and Hibernate.

SLA is a web application portal which is used to display agreement data between Organization and UPSRTC (GOI). Data may be no. of device in working condition, reporting device, non-reporting device etc. From these, penalty gets calculated and display in this portal on monthly basis.

Working scope are Core Java, Spring MVC, JSP, Ajax and JavaScript.

Software Developer

LCEPL PVT LTD

June 2018 - Jan 2019

Working with Redmine API, front-end designing and customizing in JavaScript, HTML & CSS. Migration of data and plugins with Redmine in Linux environment. Designing and coding "Node-Redmine" desktop application with NodeJs and electron

- Evaluating open source projects
- Working with Redmine & Network Infrastructure
- Front end designing and coding

TOOLS

- Eclipse-JEE Oxygen
- Eclipse-JEE Luna
- NetBeans IDE 7.0.1
- IntelliJ IDEA 2016
- Redmine 3.4.6
- SOAP UI 5.0 & Postman

PLATEFORM & SEVERS

- Linux CentOS 7.0
- JDK 6.0 , JDK 8.0
- Apache Tomcat 7.0, 8.0
- MySQL Server
- MS ACCESS

PUBLICATIONS

- Asrar Ahmad, Dr. Mohammad Atique, Dr.V.M.Thakare, "Membership Optimization for Clustering Process in Machine Intelligence- A practical approach", National conference on Innovations and Advancements in Computing, 28-29 March. 2014.
- Asrar Ahmad, Dr. Mohammad Atique, Dr. V.M.Thakare, "Optimize Data Fusion for Clustering Process A Robust Approach for Classification Problems With Outliers and Noises", IETE conference on ICon RFW, 8-10 May. 2014.
- Asrar Ahmad, Dr. Mohammad Atique, Dr. V.M.Thakare, "Comparative Analysis and Membership Optimization for Clustering Process in Machine Intelligence", ICACCI Conference on "Advances In Computing, Communication And Intelligence "At Mauritius, 23rd -29th May. 2014.

Working with web based project.

- UI Designing and coding
- Design each piece of the application and plan how the pieces will work together
- Working scope include Java EE, JSP, JavaScript, HTML/CSS and MySQL.

Visiting Faculty

SGB Amravati University

Aug 2015 -May 2018

Teaching theory and practical at Post Graduate Department of Computer Science & Engineering, Amravati University.

- Teaching Data mining and Machine learning
- Conducting workshop on Data Mining with "Weka" tool and other open source tools like Rapid Miner.

EDUCATIONS

Master of Engineering (M.E) Computer Science & Information Technology

SGB Amravati University, Amravati

2012 -2015

- Major in Data Mining and Machine Learning
- CGPA: 8.11

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E) Computer Science & Engineering

SGB Amravati University, Amravati

2007 -2011

- Major in Pattern Recognition & Image Processing
- Percent: 67.78%

Higher Secondary School (HSC)

Maharashtra State Board, India

2006-2007

Percent: 83.83%

Secondary School (SSC)

Maharashtra State Board, India

2004-2005

• Percent : 79.46%

ACHIEVEMENTS

- GATE Qualified with 320 GATE Score conducted by IIT Delhi in 2012.
- Scoring 99 marks in Physics in HSC.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Easily adjustable with new place and new people.
- Can present effectively on Technical topics.
- Resolving the conflicts.
- Maintain Interpersonal Relationships.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Father's Name: Abdul Sattar

Date of Birth: 26th February 1990

Nationality: Indian

Permanent Address: Amravati, MS,

India

Languages: English | Hindi | Urdu

Hobbies & Interest: Football | Hala

Madrid

PROJECTS & THESIS

M.E Thesis

2014

Title: Membership Optimization for Clustering Process in Machine Intelligence

Supervisor: Dr. Mohammad Atique, Dr. V.M.Thakare, S.G.B. Amravati University, Amravati.

Description: This work is to compare various data clustering techniques. Data clustering is a process of putting similar data into groups. A clustering algorithm partitions a data set into several groups such that the similarity within a group is larger than among groups. This research work reviews four of the most representative off-line clustering techniques: K-means clustering, Fuzzy C-means clustering, Mountain clustering, and Subtractive clustering algorithms. The techniques are implemented and tested against a medical problem of heart disease diagnosis. Performance and accuracy of the four techniques are presented and compared.

Tools Used: Matlab 2010, Weka tool

B.E Project

2011

Title: Lip Reading System

Supervisor: Mr. Abhijit Potey, H.V.P.M C.O.E.T. Amravati

Description: This Project is an application which allows words to be read using movement of lips. This System basically has two section i.e. User Section and Trainer section. In User section, user can read the lip by capturing the image of the lip movement via WEB-Camera. Trainer Section is used to train the system by capturing the images of various lip movements and will then be stored into the database. This system is helpful for hearing impaired to recognize the lip movements. It will be useful in Forensic Science for crime investigation. It can identify images and non-sound clippings. It will be used for image detection in image processing domain.

Technology used: Java, Java Swing,

Other Projects

- "Online Painting Auction" in JSP and Java Servlets.
- "Space Exploration" in HTML, CSS and JavaScript